weedle.com 2010-12-24

# Privacy - Weedle

Weedle’s Privacy Policy is designed to help you understand how we collect and use the personal information you consent to share, and help you make informed decisions when using Weedle, located at [www.weedle.com](http://www.weedle.com/) and its directly associated domains (collectively, “Weedle” or “Weedle Website”). 

By using or accessing Weedle, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. 

Weedle collects personal information in the form of a User Profile. The User consents to upload and create a User Profile with Weedle. The User also consents to having the User Profile accessible and available to all. 

* EU SAFE HARBOUR PARTICIPATION

We participate in the EU Safe Harbour Privacy Framework. 

* INFORMATION THAT WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT

  1. We collect information on Users in order to facilitate the operation of the Weedle Platform. 

  2. The User consents and knowingly chooses to disclose all information that is uploaded to the Weedle Platform in the form of a User Profile. When you add to your User Profile with further information about yourself, you agree that any registration information you give to Weedle will always be accurate, correct and up to date. 

  3. The Weedle Search Facility is available to all Users. Users are also invited to enter personal information which provides an enhanced set of search results. 

    1. When you sign up for a Weedle User Profile Account or other Weedle services or promotions that require registration, we ask you for personal information. For certain services, such as our advertising programs, we also request credit card or other payment account information, which we maintain in encrypted form on secure servers. We may combine the information that you submit under your account with information from other Weedle services, in order to provide you with a better experience and to improve the quality of our services. For certain services, we may give you the opportunity to opt out of combining such information. 
    2. Weedle provides an invitation service when you register with the Platform. If you choose (consent or opt in) to use our invitation service to tell a contact about our site, we will ask you for information needed to send the invitation, such as your contacts email address or we will ask you to consent to having your contact list(s) imported. We will send your contacts an email or instant message in your name inviting him or her to visit the site, and may send reminders to them. Weedle stores this information to send invitations and reminders, to register a contact connection if your invitation is accepted, to allow you to see invitations you have sent and to track the success of our referral program. All information that you enter or upload about your contacts will be covered by the same terms of this privacy policy as cover your own information. Weedle also stores this information (imported contacts information) to avoid duplication of contacts and to check when contacts, not invited by the User, join the Weedle Platform through registration. Weedle will also store the User’s access details in order to synch the contacts whenever the User logs in. 
    3. When you visit Weedle, we collect your browser type and IP address. This information is gathered for all Weedle Users. In addition, we store certain information from your browser using ‘cookies’. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the User’s computer tied to information about the User. We send cookies to your computer or other device that uniquely identifies your browser. We use session ID cookies to confirm that Users are logged in. These cookies terminate once the User closes the browser. By default, we use a persistent cookie that stores your login ID (but not your password) to make it easier for you to login when you come back to Weedle. You can remove or block this cookie using the settings in your browser if you want to disable this convenience feature. We use cookies to collect information about visitors’ use of the Weedle website. The information collected by cookies enables Weedle to understand the use of its site. This in turn helps to provide visitors with a better experience. Weedle will not attempt to personally identify visitors from their IP addresses. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service, including storing of User preferences, improving search results and ad selection and tracking User trends, such as how people search. Weedle also uses cookies in its advertising services to help advertisers and publishers serve and manage ads across the web. We may set one or more cookies in your browser when you visit a website, including Weedle sites that use our advertising cookies and that view or click an ad supported by Weedle’s advertising services. 
    4. When you access Weedle Services, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser. 
    5. When you use Weedle, you may set up your User Profile, form community networks, send messages, perform searches and queries, set up events, add applications, transmit information through various channels and send emails or other communications to Weedle. We collect this information so that we can provide you the service and offer personalised features. In most cases, we retain it so that, for instance, you can return to view prior messages you have sent or easily see your community network list. When you update information, we usually keep a back-up copy of the prior version for a reasonable period of time to enable reversion to the prior version of that information. 
    6. When you post User Content on the Site you do so at your own risk. We cannot and do not guarantee that User Content you post on the Site will not be viewed by unauthorised persons. We are not responsible for circumvention of any settings or security measures contained on the Site. You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of User Content may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other Users have copied or stored your User Content. 
    7. Weedle will store User’s access details so that when a registered User logs in and accesses the Weedle Platform Weedle will offer Users the option to sync their contacts. Weedle will ask Users to consent to having their contacts synched. If you do not wish to have your contacts synched please unselect the synch button. 
    8. Weedle have the right to reformat and move User Profiles, and User Profile information. Weedle reserve the right to remove, edit, move or close any account for any reason and to suspend or ban any User account for any reason. 
    9. We offer some of our services on or through other websites. Personal information that you provide to those sites may be sent to Weedle in order to deliver the service. We process such information under this Privacy Policy. The affiliated sites through which our services are offered may have different privacy practices and we encourage you to read their privacy policies. 
    10. Weedle may make available third-party applications through its Weedle Platform. The information collected by Weedle when you enable a gadget or other application is processed under this Privacy Policy. Information collected by the application or gadget provider is governed by their privacy policies. 
    11. Weedle may present links in a format that enables us to keep track of whether these links have been followed. We use this information to improve the quality of our search technology, customised content and advertising. 
    12. This Privacy Policy applies to the Weedle Platform and Weedle Services only. We do not exercise control over the sites displayed as search results, products or services or links from within our various Weedle Services. These other sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. 
  4. Any improper collection or misuse of information provided on Weedle is a violation of the Weedle Terms and Conditions of Use. 
  5. Weedle may also collect information about you from other sources, such as newspapers, blogs, instant messaging services and other Users of the Weedle service through the operation of the service in order to provide you with more useful information and a more personalised experience. 
  6. Weedle only processes personal information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy and/or the supplementary privacy notices for specific services. In addition to the above, such purposes include: 
    1. Providing our services, primarily making User Profiles available to all; 
    2. Providing more relevant search results by utilising data provided by the User;
    3. Auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our services;
    4. Ensuring the technical functioning of Weedle; 
    5. Protecting the rights or property of Weedle or our Users; and 
    6. Developing new services. 
  7. By using Weedle, you are consenting to have your personal data transferred to and processed in such jurisdictions as is necessary. 

* USE OF INFORMATION OBTAINED BY WEEDLE

  1. When you register with Weedle, you create your own User Profile. We may occasionally use your name and email address to send you notifications regarding new services offered by Weedle that we think you may find valuable. 
  2. User Profile information is used by Weedle primarily to be presented back to and edited by you when you access the service and to be presented to all. 
  3. The User Profile information that you submit to Weedle will be available to all Users of the Weedle Platform. All User Profile information will be available in search results generated for Users and may be made available to third-party search engines. People who see your name in searches will be able to access your User Profile information without registering with the Weedle Platform. 
  4. User Profile information is used by Weedle to improve the functionality of the Weedle Platform. 
  5. Weedle may send you service-related announcements from time to time through the general operation of the service. 
  6. Generally, you may opt out of such emails through your User Account Settings. Weedle reserves the right to send you notices about your account even if you opt out of all voluntary email notifications. 
  7. Weedle may use information in your User Profile without identifying you as an individual to third parties. We do this for purposes such as aggregating how many people are in a network like a group of electricians, and also personalising advertisements and promotions so that we can provide you with up to date Weedle promotions and sponsors of community groupings. We believe this benefits you. We may use information about you that we collect from other sources, including but not limited to newspapers and Internet sources such as blogs, instant messaging services, Weedle Platform developers and other Users of Weedle, to supplement your User Profile. Where such information is used, we generally allow you to specify in your User Account Settings that you do not want this to be done or to take other actions that limit the connection of this information to your User Profile (e.g. removing photo tag links). 

* CHILDREN AGED UNDER 14

Weedle does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 14 or knowingly allow such persons to register. If you are under 14, please do not attempt to register for Weedle or send any personal information about yourself to us, (including your name, address, telephone number or email address). No one under the age of 14 may provide any personal information to Weedle on the Weedle Platform. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 14 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. 

* CHILDREN BETWEEN THE AGES OF 14 AND 18

We recommend that children 14 years of age or older ask their parents for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet. 

* SHARING YOUR INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES

  1. Weedle is about sharing catalogued skill information with Users. We do not provide your contact information to third-party marketers without your permission. We share your information with third parties only in limited circumstances where we believe such sharing is (1) reasonably necessary to offer the service, (2) legally required or (3) permitted by you. 
  2. We may provide information to service providers to help us bring you the services we offer. Specifically, we may use third parties to facilitate our business. In connection with these offerings and business operations, our service providers may have access to your personal information for use for a limited time in connection with these business activities. Where we utilise third parties for the processing of any personal information, we implement reasonable contractual and technical protections limiting the use of that information to the Weedle-specified purposes. This site uses various analytics services to monitor and improve the quality and usability of the Weedle Platform. 
  3. If you, your contacts or members of your community network use any third-party applications developed using the Weedle Platform (“Platform Applications”), those Platform Applications may access and share certain information about you with others. You may opt out of any sharing of certain or all information through Platform Applications. In addition, third-party developers who have created and operate Platform Applications (“Platform Developers”), may also have access to your personal information (including your contact information) if you permit Platform Applications to access your data. Before allowing any Platform Developer to make any Platform Application available to you, Weedle requires the Platform Developer to enter into an agreement which, among other things, requires them to respect your privacy settings and strictly limits their collection, use and storage of your information. However, while we have undertaken contractual and technical steps to restrict possible misuse of such information by such Platform Developers, we cannot and do not guarantee that all Platform Developers will abide by such agreements. Please note that Weedle does not screen or approve Platform Developers and cannot control how such Platform Developers use any personal information that they may obtain in connection with Platform Applications. In addition, Platform Developers may require you to sign up to their own terms of service, privacy policies or other policies, which may give them additional rights or impose additional obligations on you. 
  4. We may be required to disclose User information pursuant to lawful requests, such as subpoenas or court orders, or in compliance with applicable laws. We do not reveal information until we have a good faith belief that an information request by law enforcement or private litigants meets applicable legal standards. Additionally, we may share account or other information when we believe it is necessary to comply with law, to protect our interests or property, to prevent fraud or other illegal activity perpetrated through the Weedle service or using the Weedle name, or to prevent imminent bodily harm. This may include sharing information with other companies, lawyers, agents or government agencies. 
  5. We let you choose to share information with marketers or electronic commerce providers through on-site offers. 
  6. You can share your Weedle information with outside applications and websites to make your experiences on those applications and websites better and more commercial. 
  7. We are not responsible for any third party applications and websites that you interact with through the Weedle Platform. 
  8. If you allow an application or website to connect with your Weedle account, that application or website can access information on Weedle related to you and your contacts and generate and publish stories about actions you take on that application or website without any additional permission. An application or website that you connect with can generally access the same information that you can see about yourself and your contacts, and an application or website that your contacts connect with can access the same information about you that the contacts can see. 
  9. You can report any suspected misuse of the Weedle Platform to us, and we will investigate the claim and take appropriate action. 
  10. If the ownership of all or substantially all of the Weedle business, or individual business units owned by Weedle Holdings Limited, were to change, your User information may be transferred to the new owner so the service can continue operations. In any such transfer of information, your User information would remain subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Policy. 
  11. All sharing of information is done at your own risk. 

* LINKS

Weedle may contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites. We encourage our Users to be aware when they leave our site that they should read the privacy documents of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by Weedle. 

* THIRD PARTY ADVERTISING

Advertisements that appear on Weedle are sometimes delivered (or “served”) directly to Users by third-party advertisers. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. These third-party advertisers may also download cookies to your computer or use other technologies such as JavaScript and “web beacons” (also known as “1x1 gifs”) to measure the effectiveness of their adverts and to personalise advertising content. Doing this allows the advertising network to recognise your computer each time they send you an advertisement in order to measure the effectiveness of their adverts and to personalise advertising content. In this way, they may compile information about where individuals using your computer or browser saw their advertisements and determine which advertisements are clicked. Weedle does not have access to or control of the cookies that may be placed by the third-party advertisers. 

This privacy policy covers the use of cookies by Weedle and does not cover the use of cookies or other tracking technologies by any of its advertisers. 

* CHANGING OR REMOVING INFORMATION

Access and control over most personal information on Weedle is readily available through the User Profile editing tools. Weedle Users may modify or delete any of their User Profile information at any time by logging into their account. Individuals who wish to deactivate their Weedle account may do so through your User Account Settings. Removed information may persist in back-up copies for a reasonable period of time but will not be generally available to Users of Weedle. 

Where you make use of the communication features of the service to share information with other individuals on Weedle, however, (e.g. sending a personal message to another Weedle User) you generally cannot remove such communications. 

* ACCESSING AND UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION

  1. When you use Weedle services, we make good-faith efforts to provide you with access to your personal information and either to correct this data if it is inaccurate, or to delete such data at your request if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes. We ask individual Users to identify themselves and the information that they request be accessed, corrected or removed before processing such requests and we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardise the privacy of others or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes) or for which access is not otherwise required. 
  2. You may change or delete your User Profile information at any time by going into your User Profile and editing the information. 
  3. Deactivating or deleting your account. If you deactivate your account Users will not be able to see it but it will not be deleted. Your User Profile information will be saved in the event that you wish to reinstate your User Profile information. When you delete your account however, it is permanently deleted. You will not be able to reinstate your User Profile, you will have to create a new User Profile. 
  4. Even after you deactivate or delete your User Profile you should be aware that copies of the information may remain accessible elsewhere, specifically in relation to the extent that it has been previously shared with others, or if it was copied or stored by other Users. 
  5. Removed and deleted information may persist in backup copies for a reasonable period of time (but will not be available to others). 

* SECURITY

Weedle takes appropriate precautions to protect our Users’ information. Your account information is located on a secure server behind a firewall. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number or your password), we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). 

* TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE, NOTICES AND REVISIONS

Your use of Weedle, and any disputes arising from it, is subject to this Privacy Policy as well as our Terms and Conditions of Use and all of its dispute resolution provisions including limitation on damages and choice of law. We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy and our Terms and Conditions of Use at any time. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on this site. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email or through notice on the Weedle website. We encourage you to refer to this policy on an ongoing basis so that you understand our current privacy policy. Unless stated otherwise, our current privacy policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account. 

* CHOICES FOR PERSONAL INFORMATION

  1. When you sign up to create a User Profile this requires registration, we ask you to provide personal information. If we use this information in a manner different from the purpose for which it was collected, then we will ask for your consent prior to such use. 
  2. If we propose to use personal information for any purposes other than those described in this Privacy Policy and/or in the specific service privacy notices, we will offer you an effective way to opt out of the use of personal information for those other purposes. We will not collect or use sensitive information for purposes other than those described in this Privacy Policy and/or in the supplementary service privacy notices, unless we have obtained your prior consent. 
  3. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some Weedle features and services may not function properly if your cookies are disabled. 

* INFORMATION SHARING

Weedle only shares personal information with other companies or individuals outside the Weedle Platform in the following limited circumstances: 

  1. We have your consent. We require opt-in consent for the sharing of any sensitive personal information with other companies or individuals outside the Weedle Platform. 
  2. We have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request, (b) enforce applicable Terms and Conditions of Use, including investigation of potential violations thereof, (c) detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, or (d) protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of Weedle, its Users or the public, as required or permitted by law. 
  3. If Weedle becomes involved in a merger, acquisition or any form of sale of some or all of its assets. 

* INFORMATION SECURITY

  1. We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorised access to or unauthorised alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorised access to systems where we store personal data. 
  2. Personal information may be accessed by Weedle employees, contractors and agents who require this information in order to operate, develop or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations. 

* DATA INTEGRITY

Weedle processes personal information only for the purposes for which it was collected and in accordance with this Privacy Policy or any applicable service-specific privacy notice. We review our data collection, storage and processing practices to ensure that we only collect, store and process the personal information needed to provide or improve our services or as otherwise permitted under this Policy. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information that we process is accurate, complete and current, but we depend on our Users to update or correct their personal information whenever necessary. 

* PRIVACY MATTERS

When we receive formal written or emailed complaints it is Weedle’s policy to contact the complaining User regarding his or her concerns. We will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that cannot be resolved between Weedle and an individual. 

* CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

Please note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy without your explicit consent and we expect that the majority of such changes will be minor. Regardless, we will post any Privacy Policy changes on the Weedle website.
